A Guide to the Flow Fund Circle records FA770
Rockefeller Archive Center
Flow Fund Circle records
1991-2010
Rockefeller Archive Center
Flow Fund Circle
FA770
2.47 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes 1 half-letter document box, 12 DVD/CD and 14 VHS.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Flow Fund Circle records were donated to the RAC by Marion Rockefeller Weber in 2010. All records were transferred as Accession 2010:039.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Separated Materials
Special Formats (video, digital media, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection to facilitate stabilization, migration, and long-term preservation. All pertinent items are assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Arrangement
Arranged as received.
Biographical / Historical
The Flow Fund Circle was founded in May 1991 by Marion Rockefeller Weber, daughter of Laurance S. Rockefeller and granddaughter of John D. Rockefeller Jr., as a non-traditional innovative approach to empower all people to become philanthropists and democratize the practice of philanthropy.
The FFC uses visionary creative thinking to identify and distribute funding to those in need through grassroots organic interactions with no overhead and minimal bureaucracy. The Flow Fund Circle began with five members and has expanded to more than 50.
Each Flow Fund Circle is seeded by a Donor, sometimes referred to as a Flow Fund Initiator. For example the Initiator may provide $20,000 per year for three years to a small group of individual Flow Funders. Each Flow Funder in turn can then donate their allotment to charities or organizations, in areas they identify, as they see fit. Flow Funders are advised not to donate all their resources to one project or one organization, and in turn cannot use the funding to finance their own projects. The average gift generally ranges from $250 to $2,500.
In some cases, the Donor or Initiator may seed their funds to a small group of Flow Fund Holders or Participants, and then the Holders serve to identify Flow Funders who then individually distribute the funds to charities. Flow Fund Holders or Participants are often former Flow Funders.
With Flow Funding grantees are awarded pure donations, with no prior project proposal or application process.Each year, Flow Funders submit reports documenting their giving, and meet to discuss their projects and experiences. The format and content of these reports is often as varied as the selection choices made. And the discussions and experiences help to shape the process itself as an ever evolving organism. Well over 500 grants have been made by members of the Flow Fund Circle to recipients in 45 countries, including 41 underdeveloped countries, since its inception in 1991 through the period covered by the collection.
The expansive and diverse areas of support include, but are not limited to: Advocacy, the Aged, Agriculture, Arts, Biodiversity, Children and Teens, Cultural Preservation, Disability, Disaster Relief, Ecology and Sustainability, Economic Development, Education, Health, Job Training, Media, Micro-Enterprise, Nuclear Power, Peace, Poverty, Refugees, Rehabilitation, Spirituality, Sport, Water and Women's issues.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes Flow Fund reports, financial reports, correspondence, testimonials, and a variety of associated audio-visual and digital media. Still images documenting the experience are often an itegral part of the Flow Fund reports.
- Flow Fund Reports - FFC Kazakhstan, Year 1, Enid Schreibman and Francis May, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Flow Fund Reports - FFC Kazakhstan - Seeds Project - "Development of Philanthropy", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
- Flow Fund Reports - FFC Kazakhstan, Year 2, Enid Schreibman and Francis May, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Flow Fund Member - Mira Bocharnikova - Photo Report, Kazakhstan, 2006 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
- B. Success Stories (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Flow Fund Reports - Justine and Michael Toms - New Dimensions Foundation, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Flow Fund Reports - Elias Amidon and Rabia Elizabeth Roberts, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Flow Fund Bridging Circle Reports - Elias Amidon and Rabia Elizabeth Roberts, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Flow Fund Bridging Circle Reports - Elias Amidon and Rabia Elizabeth Roberts, 2003-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Flow Fund Reports - Brazil Projects, Edmundo Barbosa, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Flow Fund Reports - Brazil Projects, Edmundo Barbosa, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Flow Fund Reports - Brazil Projects, Edmundo Barbosa, 2006-2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Flow Fund Brazil, 2009; 2010:039:001; DVD (Item 2010:039:001)
- Brazil's Circle, 2010:039:002; CD-RW (Item 2010:039:002)
- Participants - A - B (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes: Arrien, Barbosa, Bauer, Berry.
- Participants - D - H (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Includes: Damon, Halifax, Hamilton, Hoffman.
- Participants - M - O (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Includes: Suki Miller, Moss, Muller and Tiernan, Nagarajan and Swensen, Norberg Hodge, Mayumi Oda/
- Participants - P - R (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Includes: Peavey, Peiniger, Remen.
- Participants - R - S (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Includes: Roberts and Amidon, Schreibman.
- Participants - S (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Includes: Lee Swenson and Vijaya Nagarajan.
- Participants - S - T (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Includes: Swartz, Toms.
- Participants - David Jaap van Leeuwen (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Flow Fund Reports - International Society for Ecology and Culture, Helena Norberg Hodge, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Flow Fund Testimonals and Pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Koalpara West Bengal, 2003 Rya and Sonya Berry Flowfunding, Central India Narmada River, 2010:039:003; Photo Album (Box 4A, Folder 2010:039:003)
- Flow Fund Reports - Myanmar Projects Report, David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Flow Fund Reports - Angeles Arrien Foundation for Cross Cultural Education and Research, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Circle of Bridge-Makers - Angeles Arrien Foundation for Cross Cultural Education and Research, 1991-2002 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Flow Fund Reports - Circle of Bridge-Makers, Year 1, Year 2 and Year 3 - Angeles Arrien Foundation for Cultural Education and Research (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Flow Fund Reports - Myanmar Projects, David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Flow Fund Reports - Myanmar Projects, David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Flow Fund Reports - Myanmar Projects, David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Flow Fund Circle Meetings, Membership, Publications, 1992-2009 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Flow Fund Circle Meetings, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- "American Foundations: An Investigative History", by Mark Dowie (with inscription), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Cyclone Nargis Video Report by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2008 June 12-August 12; 2010:039:004; DVD-R (Item 2010:039:004)
- Cyclone Nargis Video Report by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2010:039:005; DVD (Item 2010:039:005)
- Tet Ko Ko by David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2010:039:006; DVD (Item 2010:039:006)
- Bo Min Thein by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2010:039:007; DVD (Item 2010:039:007)
- Myanmar Projects by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2009-2010; 2010:039:008; DVD (Item 2010:039:008)
- Sweet Dreams in Bagan by David van Leeuwen, 2010:039:009; DVD-R (Item 2010:039:009)
- A Desirable Rite of Passage by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2010:039:010; DVD-R (Item 2010:039:010)
- Myanmar Projects by David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2010:039:011; DVD (Item 2010:039:011)
- Myanmar Projects, David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2008-2009; 2010:039:012; DVD (Item 2010:039:012)
- For the Flow Fund Circle by Viyali, 1996 September; 2010:039:013; VHS (Item 2010:039:013)
- Sweet Dreams in Bagan by David van Leeuwen, 2010:039:014; VHS (Item 2010:039:014)
- Flow Fund Circle Burma Hill Tribe Water Project, 2010:039:015; VHS (Item 2010:039:015)
- Flow Fund Circle Final Report (2 Year) Projects in Myanmar (Burma) - David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2003; 2010:039:016; VHS (Item 2010:039:016)
- Third Flow Fund Circle, 2010:039:017; VHS (Item 2010:039:017)
- Music at Kanoo, 2010:039:018; VHS (Item 2010:039:018)
- Third Year Flow Fund by David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2010:039:019; VHS (Item 2010:039:019)
- Myanmar Flow Fund Circle, Fourth Year, 2006; 2010:039:020; VHS (Item 2010:039:020)
- Myanmar Projects for Mr. and Mrs. Lee, 2007; 2010:039:021; VHS (Item 2010:039:021)
- Third Year Flow Fund by David Jaap Van Leeuwen, 2010:039:022; VHS (Item 2010:039:022)
- A Desirable Rite of Passage by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2010:039:023; VHS (Item 2010:039:023)
- Marion Weber Flow Fund Circle - First Year Video Report by David Jaap van Leeuwen Burma Project, 2010:039:024; VHS (Item 2010:039:024)
- Pen Pals to Burma, 2010:039:025; VHS (Item 2010:039:025)
- Flow Fund Circle Final Video Report, 2010:039:026; VHS (Item 2010:039:026)
- Myanmar Projects by David Jaap van Leeuwen, 2009-2010; 2010:039:027; DVD (Item 2010:039:027)